Nagarjun Tellakula

A year of experience in handling enterprise software analysis, design and development. Worked with multi-location teams and developed enterprise data backup and recovery products, analysed the risks and security threats in the products. Worked on both product and support life cycles. GitHub Profile: https://github.com/nagarjun28

magarjun28@gmail.com

Apt. 20, Brooklands, Nutley Lane, Donnybrook, Dublin 4, Dublin, Ireland

+353 894859270

in linkedin.com/in/nagarjun-tellakula

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer Betsol Software

07/2018 - 08/2019 Bangalore, India Betsol is a Data Management and Intelligent Automation company offering products and solutions to both enterprises and consumers.

- Worked majorly on 2 projects Zmanda and Rebit.
- Improved the efficiency of the customer portal for more than 60% in the first 4 months.
- Identified security threats and risks in software developed using various tools.
- Analyzing the data and advising improvements to the client in their products to improve financially.
- Worked in the recruitment panel to interview new candidates.
- Accomplished 30 tasks 2 months prior deadline. This helped the company to win customer satisfaction from Dell.
- Secured 2 awards for excellence in performance.

Assistant Software Engineer Betsol Software

02/2018 - 05/2018 Bangalore, India Achievements/Tasks

- Developed an automated employee skill auditing software Dextrix. Managers can view the skill and endorsements within the company. Was leading the team of 5 interns to develop this project.
- Worked on recruitment questionnaire software, which was used for the company to record candidate's performance.

EDUCATION

MSc Information Systems University College Dublin

09/2019 - Present

- Thesis in data analysis and visualization.
- Quantitative data analysis using Python and R.
- Human computer Interaction and Project management
- Cyber security and threat analysis.

B.E. Computer Science and Engineering BNM Institute of Technology

08/2014 - 06/2018

- Data Analysis and Information security.
- Information Architectures and organisation.
- Software Engineering and automation Testing.
- Machine Learning and operations research.

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Rebit (05/2019 - 08/2019)

- Settings and Customer Data Migration that was being developed for Dell's support Assist.
- Involved on-site with Dell developers to design and develop the product. Helped in requirement analysis and User experience design process to enhance the effective use of the software.
- Involved to analyse the risks and impacts of implementing the software in various environments and different user interactions using .Net and C#.
- Analysed the data provided by dell to suggest various changes and future
- financial growth for various features of the software using Python, R and Tableau.

Zmanda (07/2018 - 08/2019)

- Enterprise data backup and recovery software which was built upon opensource software called Amanda.
- Worked on developing interaction scripts with Linux and Windows in Object oriented Perl and Python. Used Django framework to build API's to interact with the core module.
- Worked with AWS, Azure and Google cloud API in integrating the product to backup data online. Worked on Test driven development environment.

Dextrix (02/2018 - 05/2018)

- Automated employee skill auditing and reporting software built for Betsol emplovees
- Targeted to assess the employees and their skill development process. Developed various micro services for computations.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Team Excellence Award (06/2019)

On the successful release of phase 1 of Rebit, project the team received an appreciation from the Dell software for product satisfaction from the stakeholders.

Spot Award (01/2019)

Received the award for outstanding performance in work. Worked on 30 user stories over a period of 2 months and delivered the products 2 months before the deadline

INTERESTS

Volunteered in NGO called Bhumi to teach school children.

Active member of Computer Society of India.

Organised cricket tournament at Betsol.

State level basketball player.

Class representative for Computer science department.